With one switch, everything changes.
Particle Fever is a documentary film directed by Mark Levinson.
As the Large Hadron Collider is about to be launched for the first time, physicists are on the cusp
of the greatest scientific discovery of all time - or perhaps their greatest failure.
Self, played by Martin Aleksa.
Self, played by Nima Arkani-Hamed.
Self, played by Savas Dimopoulos.
Self, played by Monica Dunford.
Self, played by Fabiola Gianotti.
Self, played by David Kaplan.
Particle Fever is a 2013 American documentary film tracking the first round of
experiments at the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) near Geneva, Switzerland.
The film follows the experimental physicists at the European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN) who run the
experiments, as well as the theoretical physicists who attempt to provide a conceptual framework for the LHC's results.
The film begins in 2008 with the first firing of the LHC and concludes in
2012 with the successful identification of the Higgs boson.
The Communication Awards of the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine awarded a $20,000 prize for excellence in
communicating science to the general public in Film/Radio/TV to David Kaplan and Mark Levinson for "Particle Fever" on October 14, 2015.
The awards are given to individuals in four categories: books, film/radio/TV,
magazine/newspaper and online, and are supported by the W.
Keck Foundation.
The film explores themes of physics, supersymetry, cern, higgs boson.